Christopher Donaldson - Developer, London

Summary

Christopher Donaldson

I am a software developer with over 4 years of professional experience building and implementing digital product solutions. I have a proven track record of bringing value to the teams I work with through creative problem solving and pushing myself past the confines of my role. Most recently I worked at Therapy Box, filling a contracting role as a full stack developer. I worked with a team to develop their linguistic therapy application employing my skills in React native, user experience design and product development. I am currently looking for a full time position in software development where I can continue to put my skills to use.

Experience

Therapy Box

Full Stack Web Developer 2020 - 6 weeks of contracted development work

- Contributed to 2 major projects, both full stack react native applications, one involving UNICEF. I was able to quickly integrate myself with the development team and familiarise myself with the codebase.
- Rapidly adapted to a new team and environment. Patched any gaps in my knowledge, such as learning typescript, to deliver the project requirements on time.

Jamb

Product Development Coordinator 2017 - 2020

- Designed products and oversaw the development process from concept generation, to manufacture. Responsible for releasing over 20 new products including a 3.5m tall chandelier.
- Streamlined the development process by focusing on increasing the flexibility and visibility of the company's digital information. Created a product database with over 200 custom designs.
- Developed software to solve company wide administration problems such as automatic quality control reporting, product data management and project development timelines which organized the planning and budgeting of future product releases.
- Upheld good communication practice with frequent marketing presentations and provided detailed technical information to aid with the product's release.

RGK Sports Wheelchairs

Product Design Placement 2015 - 2016

- Designed bespoke wheelchairs to wildly varying customer requirements for both daily and sports use.
- Managed and contributed to the company's CAD library and improved the wheelchair drafting speed by creating automation macros and organising elements of the company's parts databases.

Education

2:1 Product Design, Bsc - Loughborough University

2013-2017

Final Year Project: The design and prototyping of an anxiety monitoring wearable device with mobile application.

Hobbies

I have been improving my software skills by creating a life organization web-app called Jean. Jean uses React.js and D3 to display and organise information about my schedule, to-do lists, projects, workouts and diet. I am also working collaboratively on other coding projects such as a git-style recipe website. I also enjoy creating digital art with both 2d and 3d mediums using photoshop and blender. I am currently learning Chinese and am working towards a HSK1 certification.

Skills

Programming		Creative Cloud		CAD	
Javascript (ES6)	6y	Photoshop	 10y	AutoCAD	5у
React (Redux, Saga)	Зу	Illustrator	7 y	Solidworks	6y
React Native (IOS,		Indesign	6y	Substance Painter	1y
Android, Web)	1y	Premier Pro	3y	Blender	4y
D3	Зу	XD	3у	zBrush	Зу
WebGL	1y				
Typescript	1y	Hardware			
Node.js	2y		_		
Material UI	2y	AWS	2y		
Wireframing	4y	Digital Ocean	3у		
Python (Django, Flask)	Зу	Linux (Ubuntu)	2y		
Java, JavaFX	Зу	Arduino	3y		
SQL	Зу	Raspberry Pi	3у		
PHP	1y	Microchip	2y		